Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ jonathanfreyphd (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Weka

Data Mining
Marketing Research

Certifications

edX Verified Certificate for Principles of Machine Learning

edX Professional Certificate for Text Mining & Analytics

edX Verified Certificate for Data Science Essentials

edX Verified Certificate for Applied Machine Learning

edX Verified Certificate for The Analytics Edge

Publications

Changes in some functional properties of freeze-dried milk made from skim milk that supported growth of psychrotrophic bacteria.

Accelerated ripening of cheese

Method to determine foaming property of reconstituted non-fat dry milk.

Analysis of Voice of Customer data through data and text mining

Food Microbiology Versus Food Trends

Patents

Process for Producing a Microwave Puffed Cheese Snack

Jonathan Frey

Co Founder and Principal Consultant at Peninsula Business Intelligence, LLC

Redondo Beach, California, United States

Summary

Director of Operations Intelligence - Data Scientist with 20 years of data mining and experimental design experience. Have perfected experimental design method of product development that uses doptimal design technique to optimize 10 key properties of product simultaneously.

Have over 30 years experience in product development in the food industry

Specialties: Data mining (Statistica, Megaputer, Angoss, Weka, Vizier, R, Python), Text mining (Themescape, SemioTagger, Wordstat, Tableau, Megaputer), experimental design (Statistica, HITS), extensive international experience, Excel

Experience

Peninsula Business Intelligence, LLC Co Founder and Principal Consultant June 2016 - Present (6 years 11 months) Redondo Beach, CA

Experfy

8 years

Data Scientist January 2016 - Present (7 years 4 months)

Data Scientist 2015 - 2016 (1 year)

Taco Bell Corporation
15 years 2 months

Director of Operations Intelligence - Data Scientist December 2009 - February 2016 (6 years 3 months)

Page 1 of 3

Responsible for data and text mining Operations, Human Resources, Finance, Legal, Quality Assurance, Information Technology and Marketing. Developed robust text and structured data models for Voice of Customer data, YELP! Restaurant reviews and Human Resources Restaurant Employee Hot line call center data using MegaPuter PolyAnalyst. Developed and implemented an IT service desk call center data and text analytic s solution which reduced average speed of answer from 15 minutes to less than 45 seconds and identifies root cause of call generation using MegaPuter PolyAnalyst. Responsible for establishing annual operational performance targets using historical operational metrics and sales data with decision tree analysis.

Director Sensory and Knowledge Discovery January 2001 - December 2009 (9 years)

Responsible for consumer testing of products and optimization of product formulations using experimental design techniques. Run a sensory department that conducts over 500 tests per year with consumers. I am responsible for data mining within Taco Bell and provide services to R&D, Operations, HR, Finance, Marketing and Marketing Research groups. Use text mining and machine learning tools.

Mars, Inc.; Masterfoods Manager Product Development August 1988 - January 2001 (12 years 6 months)

Responsible for product development for Pedigree and Whiskas. Developed data mining based product development techniques. Designed and built global palatability data warehouse used for data mining previously tested petfood to predict how new products would perform

Kraft, Inc Research Scientist June 1985 - August 1988 (3 years 3 months)

Developed lactobacillus based cheese ripening system for Cheddar and Parmesan cheese. Scaled up ultrafiltration quisecent evaporation Cheddar cheese production system a semi-works plant. Developed and received patent for microwavable Cheddar cheese chip

Education

University of Wisconsin-Madison Ph.D., Bacteriology, Food Microbiology · (1976 - 1985)